[{"id": "5fd65bbaa5bfecdd737e082e", "question": "What was the last album recorded by the Beatles?", "answer": "Abbey Road", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6bf", "question": "What acid gives vinegar its smell and taste?", "answer": "Acetic acid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59636bc0967692ea851899a6", "question": "Which two signers of the \"Declaration of Independence\" who later became US Presidents, died on July 4, 1826?", "answer": "John Adams and Thomas Jefferson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c578fbde8045e48466ad", "question": "A group of otters is called what?", "answer": "A raft", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b286", "question": "What family-planning pioneer coined the phrase \"birth control\" in 1914?", "answer": "Margaret Sanger", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393f5", "question": "What actor played the role of Jean-Baptiste Emanuel Zorg in the 1997 movie \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Gary Oldman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59220151a4edfd43a087adda", "question": "Whose autobiography is titled \"Dreams From My Father\"?", "answer": "Barack Obama's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338943", "question": "What is the name of cartoon character Charlie Brown's dog?", "answer": "Snoopy", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f710ea9e54d890926f6da", "question": "The Golden Gate Bridge connects the city of San Francisco with what?", "answer": "Marin County -- Many tourist travel across the bridge into Marin County for a view of San Francisco.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb05", "question": "Along with Indiana Ave, and Illinois Ave, what is the third third red property on a Monopoly board?", "answer": "Kentucky Ave.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a1a", "question": "What kind of creature is Mrs. Tiggy-Winkle in a book by Beatrix Potter?", "answer": "Hedgehog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f750ea9e54d890926f703", "question": "What legendary European culture hero is celebrated as an icon of beer, brewing, joviality, and joie de vivre.", "answer": "Gambrinus -- Some imagine Gambrinus as a man who has an enormous capacity for drinking beer.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59ded059ea2747c8aff16d26", "question": "In which city is the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "Vatican City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42a", "question": "In what country would you see \"whirling dervishes\"?", "answer": "Turkey", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58dba4c4874c93a3298b2148", "question": "What is the highest mountain in Wales?", "answer": "Mount Snowdon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c9", "question": "What TV show featured a character by the name of Christmas Snow?", "answer": "Three's Company", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5a9", "question": "What is an angle whose measure is between 0 and 90 degrees referred to as?", "answer": "An acute angle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b193", "question": "What year did Napoleon become the Emperor of the French?", "answer": "1804", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974a", "question": "Who was the first Ink Master contestant to compete in 2 seasons?", "answer": "Tatu Baby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133931d", "question": "In the movie \"This is Spinal Tap\", what volume does the amplifier go up to?", "answer": "Eleven", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a1", "question": "After the Civil War, which Union general became the first president of the NRA?", "answer": "Ambrose Burnside", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c88d", "question": "What does the Holmes and Rahe scale measure?", "answer": "Stress caused by life events", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60077f38bd51d85e222ab63c", "question": "In biology, a relationship between individuals of two species in which one species obtains food or other benefits from the other without either harming or benefiting the latter is called what?", "answer": "Commensalism (An example is where barnacles live on some whales and benefit by having a place to live and feed, while the whale is not harmed, but derives no benefit.)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be9c", "question": "Who washes his hands in Matthew 27:24?", "answer": "Pontius Pilate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecc5cbec223966ae8f8883", "question": "Bruce Willis played a convict turned time traveler in what 1995 movie?", "answer": "\"12 Monkeys\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1a6", "question": "What was Betty Rubble's maiden name?", "answer": "McBricker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a90", "question": "Who provides James Bond with his gadgets?", "answer": "Q", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e6bc0cfb6c85e9e634ff5b", "question": "On maps, what is the technical name for the \"you are here\" arrow?", "answer": "Ideo locator", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e6ba74fb6c85e9e634ff51", "question": "What branch of mathematics is named for the Latin for \"small pebble\"?", "answer": "Calculus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5990f559fa5fdd6dd25324ed", "question": "What was the name of the train on the TV series \"Petticoat Junction\"?", "answer": "Hooterville Cannonball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339732", "question": "How many hard-boiled eggs does Paul Newman's character eat in \"Cool Hand Luke\"?", "answer": "50", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600cc0666de0eb824d4052d9", "question": "What is the most populous city in Australia?", "answer": "Sidney", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d118174fea7fe947a22281", "question": "What metal has the chemical symbol Pb?", "answer": "Lead", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0bc", "question": "Which film director's films include \"Raging Bull\" and \"Goodfellas\"?", "answer": "Martin Scorsese", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2da", "question": "What four letters were removed form the end of Los Angeles' \"Hollywood\" sign in 1949?", "answer": "L, a, n, d", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6015e1d6fe83fe1f2a824b99", "question": "What was the \"The Blitz\"?", "answer": "A term used for Germany\u2019s bombing campaign on London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65e721f3c0ead6880d62d", "question": "Petrarch is known as the father of what school of thought?", "answer": "Humanism", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394e0", "question": "\"Mork & Mindy\" was a spin-off of what TV show?", "answer": "Happy Days", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e49", "question": "What did Ignatz Mouse enjoy throwing at Krazy Kat's head?", "answer": "A brick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339264", "question": "What three letter name did the band formerly known as \"Slut Bank and Twisted Kites\" finally settle on?", "answer": "R.E.M.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fdc0ce7469bb8041d07a056", "question": "How do you say \"Merry Christmas\" in France?", "answer": "Joyeux Noel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b53101dd7bf43be5e7cc", "question": "What is the name for the process of electing a Pope?", "answer": "Conclave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe909eb01dd7bf43be5e893", "question": "What is trepanning?", "answer": "The drilling of holes in the head and scraping or cutting of the skull", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba8c", "question": "How much does it cost to purchase Boardwalk in the standard game of Monopoly?", "answer": "$400", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a771", "question": "Which US state is home to a city called Truth or Consequences?", "answer": "New Mexico", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a80", "question": "In the Foreigner song \"Hot Blooded\", the singer has a temperature of how many degrees?", "answer": "103", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58b370d21c3f17ccc40c8e19", "question": "Under the English 1830 Beer Act, what was the cost of the licence to sell beer and cider from your own home?", "answer": "2 guineas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5e2", "question": "Which US state is closest to Cuba?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ebd", "question": "John Carpenter's \"Assault on Precinct 13\" is an homage to what classic Howard Hawks western?", "answer": "Rio Bravo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76f2aeec85e375820b2e3", "question": "Which two countries are on the southern border of Mexico?", "answer": "Guatemala and Belize", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a167", "question": "Who played Sarah Conner in the 1991 film \"Terminator 2: Judgment Day\"?", "answer": "Linda Hamilton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7cd86877e98cb97778a38", "question": "Which US state hosts the world lumberjack championship?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfef", "question": "What type of creature is located on top of the Calcutta Cup?", "answer": "Elephant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caa6", "question": "What is a group of locusts called?", "answer": "Plague", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8b94ec223966ae8f8840", "question": "\"Mi Reflejo\" was a Spanish-speaking album released by which famous musician?", "answer": "Christina Aguilera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590498aecf93664eb1048689", "question": "A statue of Lady Godiva stands in the centre which English city?", "answer": "Coventry", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef61476ce05a3942286e51", "question": "Who created Mickey Mouse along with Walt Disney?", "answer": "Ub Iwerks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ae8641c7f28483af1e7fdcd", "question": "In which year did India gain its independence from the United Kingdom?", "answer": "1947", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d0", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the river Nile?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339549", "question": "What was the name of the dog on the TV show \"The Jetsons\"?", "answer": "Astro", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cefc09b948005ec986edcdd", "question": "Who is the fourth member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Yeojin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e16506d333868d34d727", "question": "Who wrote \"The Communist Manifesto\"?", "answer": "Karl Marx and Friedrich Engels", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133997c", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is Krusty the Clown's real full name?", "answer": "Herschel Shmoikel Pinchas Yerucham Krustofsky", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a03", "question": "What disability does Rocky Dennis' girlfriend have in the 1985 film \"Mask\"?", "answer": "She is blind", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a28", "question": "Who played Richard Nixon in the 1995 film \"Nixon\"?", "answer": "Anthony Hopkins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f6", "question": "What cut of steak got its name from the New York City coach stop where it was first served?", "answer": "Porterhouse", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5a25efc56682715b82711cd8", "question": "Which Canadian province was responsible for producing the weekly newpaper publication \"Photo Journal\" until 1981?", "answer": "Quebec", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133caae", "question": "What do zoologists call the leader of a wolf pack?", "answer": "The alpha male", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8d6", "question": "Which chemical element has the atomic number 4?", "answer": "Beryllium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133922a", "question": "What Welsh songstress has performed the themes for three different Bond movies?", "answer": "Shirley Bassey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba08", "question": "Whose street name during his days as a juvenile delinquent was \"Detroit Red\"?", "answer": "Malcolm X", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338beb", "question": "What language do the majority of musical terms stem from?", "answer": "Italian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59067f54ff9c0647b50a8083", "question": "In October of 2016, just 2 months after its initial release, what product did Samsung stop manufacturing and selling?", "answer": "Galaxy Note 7", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390a6", "question": "Who wrote the opera \"Madama Butterfly\"?", "answer": "Giacomo Puccini", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339141", "question": "What was the last opera composed by Benjamin Britten?", "answer": "Death in Venice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a824", "question": "The Yalu River separates China from what other country?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bf8", "question": "What year was the movie \"Breakfast at Tiffany's\" released?", "answer": "1961", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b817", "question": "What do you need two of to play Double Dutch?", "answer": "Jump ropes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abbb", "question": "Which sea is located between Australia and New Zealand?", "answer": "Tasman Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aaaa", "question": "What is the capital of Turkey?", "answer": "Ankara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59bb2853c9bff04efae6d74f", "question": "The song \"Son of My Father\" is credited as being the first number 1 UK hit to feature which instument?", "answer": "A synthesizer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6018bb6ad96d05b23b28164e", "question": "In addition to the main Passover, there is also a second one called the Second Passover. When is the Second Passover celebrated?", "answer": "The Second Paassover (also called \"Pesach Sheni\") is observed on the 14th day of the Hebrew Calendar month of Iyar.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1e5", "question": "Which US president lived in Montpelier?", "answer": "James Madison", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fc5", "question": "Which detective story writer created the character Tuppence Beresford?", "answer": "Agatha Christie", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ce", "question": "What is the only mammal that can't jump?", "answer": "The Elephant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce8", "question": "What singer-songwriter played bass in the New Wave band \"'Til Tuesday\"?", "answer": "Aimee Mann", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58bb3558e368446ca7bd6851", "question": "What method of coffee preparation requires the beans to be ground as coarsely as possible?", "answer": "Cold brew", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b502", "question": "What do you get when you mix champagne and stout?", "answer": "A Black Velvet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bac", "question": "What band's first Top 10 hit in the US was 1984's \"Legs\"?", "answer": "ZZ Top", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aace", "question": "What is the capital of Brazil?", "answer": "Brasilia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6e", "question": "Who painted \"Water Lilies\"?", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b793", "question": "In \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", what did my true love send to me on the fifth day?", "answer": "Five gold rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acae", "question": "What date in 1929 saw the shooting of seven members of Bugs Moran's gang in Chicago?", "answer": "February 14", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b323608bf195a31e15d73b5", "question": "What character was invented to respond to questions from Gold Medal Flour customers?", "answer": "Betty Crocker", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a90f", "question": "What major river runs through Amsterdam?", "answer": "Amstel", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394da", "question": "What was Shari Lewis' hand puppet called?", "answer": "Lamb Chop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbd4c1c00d154d7af00b8cf", "question": "Who recorded the 1990's song \"Baby Got Back\"?", "answer": "Sir Mix-a-Lot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c1", "question": "Which is the largest of the Canary Islands?\u00a0", "answer": "Tenerife", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febb7957e83c707845b2131", "question": "The transition of a substance directly from the solid state to the gas state, without passing through the liquid state is called?", "answer": "Sublimation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6fe", "question": "What decade was Girl Scouts of America formed in?", "answer": "1910s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4b4549076251badbeac1", "question": "Who was the first female U.S. Attorney General?", "answer": "Janet Reno -- She served as the attorney general for President Bill Clinton's entire presidency.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921e", "question": "What does the \"L\" stand for in Samuel L. Jackson?", "answer": "Leroy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f8", "question": "What explorer disappeared in 1928 while on a rescue mission for survivors of the crashed airship \"Italia\"?", "answer": "Roald Amundsen", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c88e98222f44c2d77a29c48", "question": "Marilyn Monroe made her first movie appearance in 1947 in which film?", "answer": "Dangerous Years", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c78", "question": "Which movie introduced Indiana Jones to the public?", "answer": "Raiders of the Lost Ark", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b68406d333868d34d6f2", "question": "Which British royal family changed its name from Saxe-Coburg-Gotha in 1917?", "answer": "Windsors", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a888", "question": "What island is home to nearly all the lemurs?", "answer": "Madagascar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339224", "question": "Who celebrated is 111th birthday during \"The Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring?\"", "answer": "Bilbo Baggins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbdc", "question": "What is the name of the Cheeto's Cheetah?", "answer": "Chester", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4b8", "question": "\"Video Killed the Radio Star\" was the debut music video on which channel in 1981?", "answer": "MTV", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338908", "question": "How many spikes are there on the The Statue of Liberty's crown?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6014c52ffbde8045e48466a8", "question": "What characteristic is unique to cetacean creatures?", "answer": "A blowhole -- Cetaceans (whales, porpoises, and dolphins)  use the blowhole on top of their head to breath oxygen.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388b3", "question": "Who is the main character in Joseph Heller's novel \"Catch-22\"?", "answer": "Yossarian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fede45f6ce05a3942286ddd", "question": "Who penned the classic songs \"Bad Moon Rising\", \"Who'll Stop The Rain\", and \"Lodi\"?", "answer": "John Fogarty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a7f5ed6f5f79087132fb41", "question": "Which 1980s wrestling superstar once played baseball in the St. Louis Cardinals' minor league system?", "answer": "\"Macho Man\" Randy Savage", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff5125fff04d658268c92cf", "question": "What group of American women displayed their loyalty following the passage of the Townshend Acts in 1767?", "answer": "The\u00a0Daughters of Liberty\u00a0used their traditional skills to develope substitutes for goods sold by the British.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339458", "question": "What is Shorty's real name in the movie \"Get Shorty\"?", "answer": "Leo Devoe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133890e", "question": "Who founded the cubism movement with George Braque?", "answer": "Pablo Picasso", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389fd", "question": "Who's Kanga's son in the \"Winnie-the-Pooh\" stories?", "answer": "Roo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdc0c0b469bb8041d07a04c", "question": "What is the official flower of Easter?", "answer": "White Lilly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd6696ba5bfecdd737e087b", "question": "What was Scrabble originally called?", "answer": "Lexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d154bb53d1af65886501", "question": "In which Canadian province would you find Christmas Island?", "answer": "Nova Scotia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a15a", "question": "Whose secretary was Loelia Ponsonby?", "answer": "James Bond's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5909cc05bb53d1af658864dd", "question": "What beverage company distributed the 2012 3D animated short film \"The Polar Bears\"?", "answer": "The Coca-Cola Company", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e3", "question": "What was the middle name of composer Bach?", "answer": "Sebastian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afc4", "question": "What US first lady helped draft the Universal Declaration of Human Rights?", "answer": "Eleanor Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b327", "question": "Who was the first African American mayor of Chicago?", "answer": "Harold Washington", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d8", "question": "In the computer world, does the abbreviation DOS stand for?", "answer": "Disk Operating System", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3c2eb4f032c0db195b487", "question": "What mathematician spent his life calculating the value of pi to 707 decimal places?", "answer": "William Shanks", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60078b710eee65b76b9f2668", "question": "What name was given to Britain\u2019s policy of avoiding strict enforcement of parliamentary laws on early American colonies?", "answer": "Salutary neglect", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2d4", "question": "What does a phonophobe fear?", "answer": "Noise", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338935", "question": "Who had the Ring immediately before Bilbo took it in \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "Smeagol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd6", "question": "Who played the title character in the film \"The Omega Man\"?", "answer": "Charlton Heston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395cf", "question": "In The Simpsons, who said: \"Parades just bring out so many emotions in me\" joy, excitement, looking...\"?", "answer": "Marge Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd22bec223966ae8f88c3", "question": "What board game do the three fairies play in \"Maleficent\"?", "answer": "Nine men's morris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69b8c20565ad31a57c760", "question": "What president turned down a scholarship to Harvard?", "answer": "Richard Nixon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb7", "question": "Which building material gets its name from Arabic for \"brick\"?", "answer": "Adobe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b80c", "question": "What sport has a hooker in a scrum?", "answer": "Rugby", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e3d", "question": "What children's classic first chapter is titled \"In the Drain\"?", "answer": "Stuart Little", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc63", "question": "What year saw the release of the first Hot Wheels toy car?", "answer": "1968", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133940c", "question": "Who played Uncle Buck in the movie \"Uncle Buck\"?", "answer": "John Candy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c130", "question": "What year was boxer Arnold Raymond Cream born in?", "answer": "1914", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339755", "question": "Who played Sam Spade in the 1941 movie \"The Maltese Falcon\"?", "answer": "Humphrey Bogart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e96917ccba3ffe45786ef", "question": "Galt MacDermot wrote the music for what 1967 musical?", "answer": "Hair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b360", "question": "What were the wicks in the Vestal Virgins lamps allegedly made from?", "answer": "Asbestos", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6589bae7e414034b5aef3", "question": "Where did yoga originate?", "answer": "India", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a760", "question": "The Arc de Triumphe is to Paris, as the Brandenburg Gate is to what other European capital city?", "answer": "Berlin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e0", "question": "Which country owns the Canary Islands?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a8b720565ad31a57c7fa", "question": "What was the tiny pocket in jeans originally meant to store?", "answer": "Pocket watch", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc29", "question": "What year was football player, David Beckham, born?", "answer": "1975", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d45b2596a59cbdfbd3a2", "question": "What cells are responsible for forming new bone?", "answer": "Osteoblasts", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58b373281c3f17ccc40c8e2b", "question": "In \"The Wizard of Oz\", what was the lion in search of?", "answer": "Courage", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f93", "question": "What actress earned an Oscar nomination for her first screen appearance in \"Sayonara\"?", "answer": "Miyoshi Umeki", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3dc6c73aa70ea0b70af6", "question": "Which state was named for the color red?", "answer": "Colorado (Spanish explorers used their native adjective for \"red\" \u2014 Colorado \u2014 to describe the present-day Colorado River.)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe773cceec85e375820b30d", "question": "The Cherokee rose is the state flower of which U.S. state?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339636", "question": "Which Disney's cartoon character's love interest is named John Smith?", "answer": "Pocahontas'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133977a", "question": "What was the sequel to The Naked Gun?", "answer": "The Naked Gun 2 1/2: The Smell of Fear", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a402", "question": "Which city has the world's largest castle complex?", "answer": "Prague, Czech Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff212b431a458464a93c44b", "question": "Originally, Jack-O'-lanterns were made from which type of vegetable?", "answer": "Turnip", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e66", "question": "Who provided the original voice for Garfield?", "answer": "Lorenzo Music", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338924", "question": "Which superhero team is Reed Richards a member of?", "answer": "The Fantastic Four", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c7", "question": "What is the name of Warren Beaty's famous sister?", "answer": "Shirley MacLaine", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d84", "question": "What time-travel film was shot on Michigan's three-mile-long Mackinac Island?", "answer": "Somewhere in Time", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601de9f76b1208747aa7e9d5", "question": "In the Chinese zodiac, with which of the five elements is the snake associated?", "answer": "Fire -- It points to aggression and dominance.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c2", "question": "What kind of company did Veronica run in the TV show \"Veronica's Closet\"?", "answer": "Mail order lingerie company", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7360deec85e375820b258", "question": "What was the name of the doctor who treated John Wilkes Booth's fractured leg after he shot President Lincoln?", "answer": "Dr. Samuel Mudd", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ad", "question": "In what city would you find Griffith Park?", "answer": "Los Angeles", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a674", "question": "Which state is located between Maine and Vermont?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a633", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Peace Garden State\"?", "answer": "North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b3f", "question": "What children's book by Louis Sachar features a palindromic protagonist named Stanley Yelnats?", "answer": "Holes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60137186138175489539638b", "question": "Who served as butler to the von Trapp family in \"The Sound of Music\"?", "answer": "Franz -- He spent several years as a loyal butler in the service of the Von Trapp family before he betrayed them to the Nazis.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cab1", "question": "What is the study of inland waters called?", "answer": "Limnology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390ed", "question": "In popular literature, what is Princess Aurora's better-known name?", "answer": "Sleeping Beauty", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078099bd51d85e222ab645", "question": "What art critic was influential in popularizing the work of Jackson Pollock?", "answer": "Clement Greenberg, a prominent art critic, is best remembered for his promotion of the abstract expressionist movement.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7c917877e98cb977789ee", "question": "Where is the centuries-old Maiden Tower?", "answer": "Baku, Azerbaijan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b359", "question": "How did Al Capone die?", "answer": "Syphilis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ca3bec44f0f6af5b066629", "question": "What Canadian professional snooker player is nicknamed \"The Grinder\"?", "answer": "Cliff Thorburn", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bbedd96d05b23b281651", "question": "The Peloponnesian War was fought between Athens and which other ancient Greek state?", "answer": "Sparta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339660", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what is the name of Marge's mother?", "answer": "Jacqueline Bouvier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fc841db78d18506ae1fe488", "question": "What is the capital of Trinidad and Tobago?", "answer": "Port of Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aeb7", "question": "Which American statistician founded the institute of Public Opinion in 1935?", "answer": "Gallup", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596dfd319616e6c6d4eba4f4", "question": "What is a baby swan called?", "answer": "A Cygnet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5a6", "question": "When was the first Wal-Mart store opened?", "answer": "1962", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c31a", "question": "Approximately how many miles are there in a nautical mile?", "answer": "1.15", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76a", "question": "What sea borders China to the east and north, and South Korea to the west?", "answer": "Yellow Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338950", "question": "What Mozart opera focuses on fiancee swapping as its theme?", "answer": "Cosi fan tutte", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abe4", "question": "What two countries share land borders with Tunisia?", "answer": "Algeria and Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b32a", "question": "Florence Nightingale tended the soldiers in which war?", "answer": "Crimean", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c53e", "question": "The bone patella is also known as what?", "answer": "The kneecap", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a20", "question": "What was subtitled \"The American Tribal Love/Rock Musical\"?", "answer": "Hair", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5cefc060948005ec986edcda", "question": "Who is the first member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Heejin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe522ee1bf59ab7d2e380ec", "question": "Tea leaves rolled into small round pellets are called what?", "answer": "Gunpowder tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b632", "question": "In NATO's phonetic alphabet, what is the letter \"B\" referred to as?", "answer": "Bravo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d03", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Barney Fife?", "answer": "Sheriff Andy Taylor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f754da9e54d890926f709", "question": "Minnesota, it is illegal to be what in bed?", "answer": "Naked", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a93620565ad31a57c7ff", "question": "John Henry \"Doc\" Holliday died as a result of what disease?", "answer": "Tuberculosis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2ae", "question": "Which effect makes the average Earth's temperature around 15 degrees centigrade?", "answer": "The greenhouse effect", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59071f1e3745b36be73039e8", "question": "What is the full name of Em Cypress, Dana's sister and reviver, in the comic book series \"Revival\"?", "answer": "Martha Ann Cypress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133897c", "question": "How many puppies did Missis Pongo give birth to in the book \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "15", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab1ac7baab681b09292196", "question": "Which car is considered to be the first hot hatchback, introduced in the 1970s?", "answer": "The Simca 1100 TI", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc7f", "question": "To counter slipping sales, what was marketed, beginning in 1987, as \"the other white meat\"?", "answer": "Pork", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf2", "question": "In which city was the composer Ludwig Van Beethoven born?", "answer": "Bonn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ec23a98dc25ca9e12ef632", "question": "What word describes \"a series of rulers from the same family\"?", "answer": "Dynasty", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6007849bbd51d85e222ab65c", "question": "What was the first fruit that was eaten on the moon?", "answer": "Peach", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d9", "question": "On what namesake Asian island were the first Homo erectus fossils found?", "answer": "Java", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b827", "question": "What US state borders only one other?", "answer": "Maine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a508", "question": "The city of Machu Picchu is located in which country?", "answer": "Peru", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c42e", "question": "What period saw the first dinosaurs?", "answer": "Triassic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefbe1f6ce05a3942286ee8", "question": "The film \"The African Queen\" is set during what war?", "answer": "World War I", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b957", "question": "What golfer is nicknamed the \"Golden Bear\"?", "answer": "Jack Nicklaus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf8", "question": "What J.D. Salinger character never found out where the ducks in Central Park go during the winter?", "answer": "Holden Caulfield", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f0e", "question": "Filmmaker Duncan Jones is the son of which British Glam Rock legend?", "answer": "David Bowie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5efa9496ccb363a2cbc5227a", "question": "Elton John sang that his \"future lies beyond\" what?", "answer": "The Yellow Brick Road", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5902a066cad1ec93f27df76a", "question": "Which Bohemian city gave us the Pilsner?", "answer": "Pilsen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b616", "question": "What does \"Aardvark\" mean in Afrikaans?", "answer": "Earth pig", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc64", "question": "How many different car models were there in the first Hot Wheels release in 1968?", "answer": "16", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b8fee662d71a5365102b", "question": "Which character opens the novel \"The Great Gatsby\"?", "answer": "Nick Carraway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078124bd51d85e222ab648", "question": "Vincent van Gogh painted \"The Starry Night\" while what?", "answer": "He painted\u00a0it while undergoing treatment at the Saint-Paul-de-Mausole,\u00a0a psychiatric hospital\u00a0in Saint-R\u00e9my-de-Provence.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c10f", "question": "Philippe Pages became famous as who?", "answer": "Richard Clayderman", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c53d", "question": "Where in your body is your patella?", "answer": "The knee", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597743a3284458f1d785442a", "question": "Who wrote the book \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Charles Dickens", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad20", "question": "Which confectioner invented the heart-shaped Valentine's Day candy box?", "answer": "Richard Cadbury", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0c4", "question": "Who sang the song \"Beat It\"?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4dd7306d333868d34d702", "question": "Ayatollah Khomeini called for a fatwa on which author of 1988's \"The Satanic Verses\"?", "answer": "Salman Rushdie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fffa78373838c5c8a417f39", "question": "What kind of animal is a bustard?", "answer": "Bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133950f", "question": "Who voiced the character Atta in the movie \"A Bug's Life\"?", "answer": "Julia Louis Dreyfuss", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5937ea7a08d98002fdd633a3", "question": "Assam, darjeeling and oolong are all types of what?", "answer": "Tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a9c", "question": "According to one popular interpretation, what does \"Pinocchio\" mean in Italian?", "answer": "Pine eyes", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3bb", "question": "What sea does the Danube empty into?", "answer": "The Black Sea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c589", "question": "What is an Anhinga?", "answer": "A bird", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a19b", "question": "Belle, Spike, Olaf, Marbles, and Andy are siblings of which Peanuts character?", "answer": "Snoopy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8d5cec223966ae8f8852", "question": "What is the name of the leader of the gang that often assaulted Andy in prison in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Bogs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f1", "question": "A Phon is a unit of what?", "answer": "Loudness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e5", "question": "What two neighboring beaches in Rio de Janeiro each inspired hit songs?", "answer": "Copacabana and Ipanema", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339441", "question": "Where does the platoon in the movie \"Full Metal Jacket\" attend boot camp?", "answer": "Parris Island", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b074", "question": "The first vending machines in the US dispensed what?", "answer": "Chewing gum", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a3", "question": "What color is Shrek?", "answer": "Green", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c58c", "question": "What celestial body orbits the Earth?", "answer": "The moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b571b7067df192a942e3369", "question": "Managua is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Nicaragua", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a155", "question": "Who married actress Julia Roberts in 1993?", "answer": "Lyle Lovett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c89e", "question": "Which element of the periodic table is named after the seventh planet from the sun?", "answer": "Uranium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3d7", "question": "Who tore up a picture of the Pope on US television in 1992?", "answer": "Sinead O'Connor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339403", "question": "Who played Al Pacino's attorney in the 1993 movie \"Carlito's Way\"?", "answer": "Sean Penn", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7122a9e54d890926f6db", "question": "Which country claims the island of Saipan as a commonwealth?", "answer": "USA -- Saipan is part of the Northern Mariana Islands, which is a commonwealth of the U.S.  Saipan is the seat of the government.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefbe446ce05a3942286eeb", "question": "In the film \"Red Dragon,\" Hannibal Lector speculates Will Graham is wearing what brand of shaving lotion?", "answer": "Old Spice", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a162ac7f01ec323f8491725", "question": "In 1967 what new safety measure and device were introduced to the UK?", "answer": "Blood alcohol level and the breathalyzer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a728cf36bcd28c11938328e", "question": "What is Steganography?", "answer": "The practice of concealing a message within another message", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c490", "question": "What is the term for a group of pet cats?", "answer": "A clowder", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c14", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the sixth plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Boils", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f7", "question": "Whose treasure is said to be the subject of the \"Treasure Island\" map?", "answer": "Captain Flint's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a4a999b61d1b4d384d5d69d", "question": "Who portrayed Marshal Matt Dillon in the TV show \"Gunsmoke\"?", "answer": "James Arness", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921f", "question": "What is the collective name for Italian-made western movies?", "answer": "Spaghetti westerns", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f81001dd7bf43be5e83e", "question": "Pteromerhanophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Flying", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1d6", "question": "What Native American was born Goyathlay?", "answer": "Geronimo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f1", "question": "What Agatha Christie novel was made up of two parts - England and Egypt?", "answer": "Death on the Nile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "601b4bff49076251badbeacb", "question": "Which U.S. President had the most children?", "answer": "John Tyler -- The 10th president had 16 children \u2014 15 with his two wives and one born out of wedlock.", "category": "history"}]